Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
It seems you've refused to allow
the interrogation of the pilot of Unit 01,
the only one directly involved
in the incident, Major Katsuragi.
Yes, Sir. He is very unstable,
emotionally speaking.
I believe that it would be
unwise to have him here.
Then, as his proxy, let us ask you,
Major Katsuragi.
In this incident,
did the Angel not attempt to
communicate with us, mankind?
I find no suggestion of that
in the subject's report.
It is believed to have been an irregular incident.
Assuming his memory is correct.
There is no evidence that his memory
has been tampered with.
However, the Eva's AC recorder
was not functioning.
There's no way to confirm it.
Was the Angel interested in the human psyche?
In the human mind?
I am unable to answer that question.
Whether the Angels even have
a concept of what a mind is,
or whether they can understand
human thoughts or not,
is completely unknown.
This incident has a new element in it,
in that the Angel tried to take an Eva into itself.
Is there any possibility that this
may be linked to the predicted Thirteenth Angel
and all Angels thereafter?
Based on the pattern thus far,
there is nothing to suggest such a systematic
organization among the Angels.
Correct! It is obvious that they have
worked independently, so far.
What do you mean, Sir?
You are not allowed to ask questions.
Yes, Sir.
That will be all. Dismissed.
What do you think, Ikari?
The Angels are beginning to attain intelligence.
The time left to us is...
EPISODE 17
THE FOURTH
QUALIFIED
INDIVIDUAL
Running short?
The patient in Room 12?
The emergency room patient
from that E incident, right?
She's been hospitalized here for a long time.
I've heard her injuries are really complicated.
She's still in elementary school.
He's here again today, right?
Yeah, he comes to see her
at least twice a week.
He's a good and caring brother.
Suzuhara
Empty
Yeah, boys like that are pretty rare these days.
Rei, are you all right today?
Yes, Sir. I will go see Dr. Akagi tomorrow,
and the day after I'll be at school.
How is school?
No problems, Sir.
I see. That's good.
Stand! Bow! Sit down!
Today's absences are the usual Ayanami,
and Aida?
What's up with Kensuke?
Mr. Koike is also absent today,
New Yokosuka. Chasin' battleships again today.
So the class in modern Japanese
will be self-study.
A ship called Myoko, or somethin'
like that, is in port.
And finally, the student
on duty today will be...
Suzuhara.
Yes, Sir!
Deliver the printouts to Ayanami after school.
Anyway, 1st Branch is okay, right?
Send the info from Satellite 5 immediately.
It's top priority.
Just the schedule for Unit 04 is fine.
It doesn't matter, we'll have the Magi evaluate
the data discrepancies from the sensors!
I'd like confirmation on the synchro data
and the S2 engine.
We'll get rid of the noise over on our end.
Just send us the originals.
It vanished?!
You're sure the 2nd Branch just vanished?!
Yes, Sir, it's been confirmed.
It vanished.
Oh, man...
The Administration and Investigation
departments are going crazy,
and General Affairs is in a total panic.
So what was the cause?
We still don't know.
Our only clues are these
geosynchronous satellite photos.
There's nothing else left.
10 seconds...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Contact.
This is horrible.
Evangelion Unit 04 and all related
research facilities within an 89km radius
have completely vanished.
Along with several thousand people.
Looking at the time schedule,
we believe it to be an accident
during the experimental installation of
the S2 engine that was restored in Germany.
Potential causes range from
a lack of structural integrity to
a preliminary design stage error.
That's 32,768 possibilities right there.
And there's also the chance of sabotage.
But it didn't explode, it vanished, right?
In other words, it disappeared.
In all probability, they were swallowed
by a Sea of Dirac,
just like Unit 01 was.
And the S2 engine that we finally restored?
Gone. Our dream's been shattered.
That's what we get for trying to push ourselves
into using something we don't understand.
That goes for the Evas too.
So, what about the remaining Unit 03?
We're going to base it here.
It seems the U.S. Government doesn't
want to lose the 1st Branch as well.
They're the ones who insisted on
the right to build Units 03 and 04.
And now they're foisting just
the dangerous parts off on us?
Talk about self-serving bastards.
After a disaster like that,
anyone would get nervous.
So what are you going to do
about the activation test?
Will you use that dummy plug?
I've still got to decide that.
This is the dummy plug prototype.
Rei's personal data has been loaded into it,
but it's not really possible to digitize
a human mind and soul.
Ultimately, it's a fake, an imitation.
Just a machine that emulates
a pilot's thinking process.
It'll transmit a signal pattern to the Eva.
As long as the Eva believes there's a pilot
and synchronizes, that's enough.
Load the data into Unit 01 and Unit 02.
There are still some problems with it.
That's not important. As long as
the Eva activates, it's sufficient.
Yes, Sir.
I've delegated the transportation
of the Unit to the U.N.
It should arrive by the end of the week.
You take care of the rest.
Yes, Sir.
We'll perform the modifications
and activation test in Matsushiro.
What about the test pilot?
The dummy plug is still risky.
Of our prospective candidates...
We'll select a fourth, then?
Yes, there is one child whose core
can be prepared immediately.
Then I'll leave it to you.
Yes, Sir.
Rei, you can come out now.
Let's eat.
Yes, Sir.
Stand! Bow!
Lunch time! Lunch time! This is the
single best thing 'bout school.
What?!
You didn't bring lunch?
I didn't have time to cook last night
because of homework.
And so you're telling me to go without lunch?!
What's this? Married couple fightin' again?
It's not like that!
What's all this formality for?
It's the Unit 03 activation test at Matsushiro.
We'll be using the fourth as the pilot.
The fourth?
The Fourth Child's been found?
Just yesterday.
But I haven't received a report
from the Marduk Institute.
The official documents will be
delivered tomorrow.
Dr. Akagi, aren't you hiding
something from me again?
Not really.
Well, okay. So, who's the selected kid?
Of all the people, it's that child?
It can't be helped.
All the candidates were gathered
together for protection.
It'll be hard to break to them.
Asuka will be fine. Her pride's
riding on her piloting of the Eva.
And Rei is an exception,
but nothing good comes of becoming
involved with us and the Evas.
Shinji understands that better than anybody.
I don't want him to suffer any more hardships.
But we need children of this kind,
in order for us all to survive.
Let go of the pure ideals,
is that what you're saying?
Suzuhara, you're on duty this week,
so get to it!
What do you mean?
The printout!
Emergency Evacuation Training
Enforcement Notice
Didn't our teacher tell you to deliver this?
C'mon, class rep, you can ask
the other person on duty.
Miss Ayanami is absent today!
It's Ayanami and me?
Can't be helped then.
But I can't exactly go to a girl's place alone.
Well, in that case, I'll go along...
Shinji!
Walk home with me, will ya?
Ayanami, we're coming in.
I don't think it's good to barge into
a girl's room without her permission.
We've got no choice.
She won't see it if we leave it there.
Excuse us...
Wha?!
Is this a girl's room? It's so unwelcomin'.
Notice
Class News
Hey, you shouldn't touch anythin'!
She'll get pissed!
I'm just cleaning up.
I ain't helpin'!
That's not a man's job!
Okay, but Miss Misato hates guys like that.
I don't care! It's my policy!
Man, what a change.
In what?
You.
The first time I saw you,
I really thought you were a jerk.
And you didn't seem like you'd
do somethin' for others.
Well, I guess it depends on
what you've got to give.
We're visitin'!
What?
Those are the printouts that were pilin' up.
I'm sorry.
I took it upon myself to clean up a little.
But I didn't touch anything except trash.
Thank you.
Eva pilots sure are weird, all right.
Thank you...
Words of gratitude.
Words I've never used.
I'd never even said them to him.
The city, a paradise made by mankind.
Once driven from Paradise,
man had no choice but to escape to this
earthly existence, side by side with death.
Our own paradise,
created by the resourcefulness that this
weakest of beings was forced to develop.
To protect ourselves from the fear of death,
to satiate our thirst for pleasure,
a paradise we created ourselves.
This city's truly such a paradise.
A armed city made to protect us.
A city of cowards fleeing from
the outside world, filled with enemies.
Cowards do live longer. That's fine.
New Tokyo-3, Nerv's camouflaged
intercept fortress.
The continually-delayed seventh
construction phase will be finished soon.
At long last, it will be completed.
How will you report Unit 04's accident
to the Committee?
Just as the facts state, the cause is unknown.
But at this stage, it's a catastrophic loss.
Unit 04 and the 2nd Branch are acceptable.
Even with the S2 engine,
we may have lost the sample,
but we still have the data in Germany.
This installation and Unit 01 will be sufficient.
But the Committee was furious.
Of course, it was an unscheduled accident.
Seele must also be frantically
adjusting the schedule.
Incidents not depicted in the
Dead Sea Scrolls can occur.
This ought to teach the old men a lesson.
The intercept system here is finally
going to be completed,
and there isn't even one measly party planned?
Nerv sure is an uptight organization.
Well, you know how Commander Ikari is.
What about you?
Are you serious, Mr. Kaji?
I'll tell Miss Katsuragi and Dr. Akagi.
I'll cover up your mouth first...
So how's work going?
Oh, it's going, I guess.
Well, I have work to do. Excuse me.
Far be it from me to comment
on your private life,
but would you keep your hands off
our young girls in this emergency situation?
This isn't your jurisdiction, though, is it?
Could I hit on you then?
That depends on how you answer my questions.
You know the secrets of Adam down there
and the Marduk Institute, right?
What secrets?
Don't play dumb!
Asking for help isn't like you.
I can't afford to care right now.
I don't have that luxury.
What's behind the oh-so-convenient
discovery of the Fourth Child?
I'll tell you one thing.
The Marduk Institute doesn't exist.
Nerv itself is pulling the strings.
Nerv itself?
Commander Ikari?
Go check out Code 707.
707?
Shinji's school?
Miss Misato!
What is it?
Miss Ritsuko wants to see you about
the business trip you're going on tomorrow.
All right. Thank you.
I'll catch you later.
Yes, Ma'am.
How about it? Wanna go out for tea?
You know, I'm a boy.
I thought you'd be a more
serious person, Mr. Kaji.
Once you're comfortable around someone,
you sure don't hold back, Shinji Ikari.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry too. I didn't mean
to sound sarcastic.
I know! I'll show you something neat.
Are they watermelons?
Yeah, aren't they cute? This is my hobby.
It's a secret from everybody else, though.
Making something...
Nurturing something is really great.
You can see and learn so many things
from the process.
Like what's enjoyable.
And about suffering too, right?
Do you hate suffering?
I don't like it.
Have you found anything that you enjoy?
That's fine too.
But knowledge of suffering makes you
all the more capable of kindness to others.
Because that's different from being weak.
Yes? Hello?
It's Katsuragi.
She says they're starting the synch test.
Fix the depth at 3.2.
I thought so. Shinji's synch rate is dropping.
LCL thickness is nominal.
Harmonics level is negative 1.1...
What's that mean?
I can't say.
0.5...
But something must have happened
during that incident.
0.9...
0.10...
Something psychological.
Current exponent is 0.9.
This makes it even harder to tell him
about Unit 03's pilot.
All results posted to Melchior.
But the pilot will be officially informed tomorrow.
Stand! Attention! Bow!
Lunch time!
Toji Suzuhara of Class 2-A.
Toji Suzuhara, report to the Principal's Office.
What the...
Did you do something?
No, nothin' comes to mind.
Principal's Office
Excuse me, I'm Toji Suzuhara.
You're Toji Suzuhara?
How was your trip to New Yokosuka yesterday?
Way cool!
Speaking of which, I picked up
some interesting information.
Eva Unit 03?
Yeah, the one they were building in America.
It's completed, isn't it?
I don't know.
I know you've got to keep it a secret,
but please tell me.
I really haven't heard anything!
Haven't you heard the rumor
that the activation test
will be held at the second test facility
in Matsushiro?
I haven't.
The pilot hasn't been chosen yet, right?
I don't know about that stuff.
I wish Miss Misato would pick me for it.
Hey, Shinji, would you ask her for me too?
I want to be an Eva pilot!
Really, I don't know.
Then what about the story
that Unit 04's been lost?
What was that?
You really don't know about that either?
It disappeared along with the entire 2nd Branch.
I heard my dad's section was in a panic.
Really?
Probably.
I haven't heard anything from Miss Misato.
Well, I guess it doesn't concern
pilots out on the line.
If she didn't tell you, it's likely because
you don't need to know.
Sorry about bothering you with weird questions.
But Toji sure is taking a long time.
Thus, we, mankind,
survived the hell on Earth called
the Second Impact and rose again.
The number of children has
been decreasing yearly...
Sorry I'm late.
I've already heard. Take your seat.
Anyway, it is you, the younger generation,
who will lead the way to the future...
Come on, let's go home.
What about Toji?
He'll be late.
He's got class duty.
The school is now closing.
All students must go home immediately.
Suzuhara!
You're on duty,
so make sure you line up the desks
and write up the daily record.
I haven't had lunch yet.
I'll do it as soon as I've eaten.
Suzuhara, you always buy your lunch
from the school co-op.
It's not like I've got anyone to cook for me.
Suzuhara...
Milk
I have two sisters, named Kodama and Nozomi.
I always cook lunch for them, but...
Must be a lot of work.
So, I'm actually a good cook,
though you might not think it.
Really?
And I always end up cooking
too much for our lunches.
What a waste.
If you need help gettin' rid
of your leftovers, I'll help.
Yes, help me.
District 3 transformation test complete.
Mr. Kaji?
Oh, Asuka? Sorry, I'm a little busy
right now. Later, okay?
But you make time for Misato.
Hey, not right now!
These are our synch data reports, right?
Four of them?
What in the hell is this? What's going on?
Why is HE the Fourth Child?
No! I don't understand! What is this?!
NERV 1st BRANCH, USA
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Eva Unit 03 is delivered to Matsushiro
from America for the activation test.
Unaware of the coming tragedy,
people gloried in the last of their daily lives.
Next episode: "The Selection of Life"
THE SELECTION OF LIFE